EDUARDO DONOSO

⊠ eduardo@soijen.com

SUMMARY

I care about living my life with two themes in mind: sustainability and the outdoors.

My love for the outdoors was born years ago during my work in the Chilean Coast Guard, sailing and patrolling the pristine Patagonian fjords.

In 2015 I traded untouched nature for big city life, when I moved from Chile to the US. As a Market Manager in GrowNYC, I connected communities with their local farmers markets. I learned the ins-and-outs of maintaining a lifestyle that is less impactful to our environment.

My writing is an intersection of these two passions - engaging curious explorers with my adventures in the mountains, sea and beyond, while promoting sustainable travel and living.

I have lived and worked in the US and Chile and have travelled to 15 countries across Europe, Africa, Asia and the Americas.

LANGUAGES

Spanish	****
English	****
Japanese	*
French	*

KNOWLEDGE

Public Speaking	****
Leadership	****
Social Media Mgmt	****
SEO	****

TOOLS

Adobe Illustrator	***
Adobe Photoshop	***

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Travel Writer January 2018 - Present

Writing about sustainable travel and the outdoors for Spanish speaking audiences. Publishing weekly through at edonoso.com.

Sóijen

Co-founder: January 2018 - Present

Soijen.com is a website that connects outdoor adventurers to off-the-beatenpath spots in Patagonia. We create content such as informational articles, photos and videos to highlight less-travelled destinations in Chilean Patagonia, while partnering with local agencies to increase their visibility and online presence.

GrowNYC New York, USA

Market Manager: May 2016 – November 2017

GrowNYC is a non-profit organization that aims to improve the lives and communities of New Yorkers through environmental programs and initiatives. I worked with the Greenmarket program as a Market Manager for the Poe Park and 175th Street Farmers Markets.

- Managed daily operations for Farmers Market in the Bronx and Manhattan.
- Connected New York City communities with their local farmers through outreach programs, educational activities and tabling events, to increase awareness of local, healthy and fresh food.
- Communicated with customers in English and Spanish and translated marketing material and infographics to Spanish.

Chilean Navy Chile (different locations)

Coast Guard Officer: February 2004 – February 2015

My responsibilities in the Coast Guard of Chile focused on the protection of lives at sea, as well as being a guardian of the marine environment and natural resources. My roles included:

- Training and Development Manager: Supervising training programs for 120 Midshipmen. Leading classes, simulations, conferences and workshops aboard the Sail Training Ship "Esmeralda" in the Tall Ship Race "Velas Latinoamerica 2014", as we sailed to 12 different countries.
- Commander of Patrol Boat: Overseeing the complete operation of a rescue patrol boat in the Patagonian fjords of southern Chile. Leading a crew of 8 in various maritime activities, such as search and rescue, lighthouse maintenance and supporting local communities.

EDUCATION

Naval Polytechnic Academy Viña del Mar, Chile Bachelor's in Marine Engineering Management: 2006 – 2012 Coast Guard, First in Class

Thesis: The role of the Coast Guard in aquaculture development in the Patagonian fjords.

Arturo Prat Naval Academy Valparaíso, Chile Associate's Degree in Naval Science: 2004-2006 Naval Academy for Cadets, Coast Guard, First in Class